I have a two-year-old daughter named Naya
لدي طفلة عمرها سنتان واسمها نايا
who is under the mistaken impression
وهي تعتقد خاطئة
that this conference is named in honor of her father.
أنه قد تمت تسمية هذا الؤتمر باسم والدها تكريمًا له.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Who am I to contradict my baby girl?
ومن أنا حتى أعارض ابنتي الصغيرة؟
As many of you know, there's something about becoming a parent
كما يعلم معظمكم، عندما تصبح أبًا
that concentrates the mind on long-term problems like climate change.
فإن العقل يبدأ بالتركيز على المشكلات طويلة الأمد مثل التغيرات المناخية.
It was the birth of my daughter that inspired me
لقد كان يوم ميلاد ابنتي مصدر إلهامٍ لي
to launch this climate organization,
لإطلاق مؤسسة المناخ هذه،
in order to counteract the excessive polarization of this issue
من أجل التصدي للاستقطاب المفرط لهذه المسألة
in the United States,
في الولايات المتحدة،
and to find a conservative pathway forward.
ولإيجاد طريق معتدل للتقدم.
Yes, folks, a Republican climate solution is possible,
نعم، أيها الناس، الحل الجمهوري للمناخ ممكن،
and you know what?
أو تعرفون؟
It may even be better.
وقد يكون أفضل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Let me try to prove that to you.
اسمحوا لي أن أثبت لكم ذلك.
What we really need is a killer app to climate policy.
ما نحتاجه حقًا هو تطبيق خارق لكل السياسات المناخية.
In the technology world, a killer app is an application so transformative
في عالم التكنولجيا، التطبيق الخارق هو تطبيق تحولي
that it creates its own market,
يصنع سوقه الخاص بنفسه،
like Uber.
مثل أُوبر.
In the climate world,
في المناخ العالمي،
a killer app is a new solution so promising
التطبيق الخارق هو حل جديدُ وواعدُ
that it can break through the seemingly insurmountable
والذي يمكنه اختراق ما لا يمكن اختراقه
barriers to progress.
من حواجز نحو التقدم،
These include the psychological barrier.
والتي من بينها أيضًا الحواجز النفسية.
Climate advocates have long been encouraging their fellow citizens
يشجع مؤيدو المناخ باستمرار المواطنين
to make short-term sacrifices now
ليقوموا الآن ببعض التضحيات قصيرة المدى
for benefits that accrue to other people
من أجل الفوائد التي ستعود على أشخاص آخرين
in other countries 30 or 40 years in the future.
في دول أخرى خلال 30 أو 40 سنة في المستقبل.
It just doesn't fly because it runs contrary to basic human nature.
لكنها لا تنتشر لأنها تعارض الطبيعة البشرية.
Next is the geopolitical barrier.
ثم نجد الحاجز الجيوسياسي.
Under the current rules of global trade,
بموجب القواعد الحالية للتجارة العالمية،
countries have a strong incentive to free ride off the emissions reductions
فإن للدول حافز قوي للتخلص من تخفيض الانبعاثات
of other nations,
للدول الأخرى،
instead of strengthening their own programs.
بدلا من تدعيم برامجهم.
This has been the curse
هذا قد يكون لعنة
of every international climate negotiations, including Paris.
لكل مفاوضات البيئة العالمية من ضمنها اتفاقية باريس.
Finally, we have the partisan barrier.
وأخيراً، حاجز الحزبية.
Even the most committed countries --
حتي أكثر الدول التزاماً --
Germany, the United Kingdom, Canada --
ألمانيا، المملكة المتحدة ، كندا--
are nowhere near reducing emissions at the required scale and speed.
ليسن قريبةً حتى من تقليل الانبعاثات بالسرعة والمستوى المطلوبين.
Not even close.
وليست على مقربة منها حتى.
And the partisan climate divide is far more acute
والحزبية المناخية هي أكثر حدة
here in the United States.
هنا في الولايات المتحدة.
We are fundamentally stuck,
نحن أساساً عالقون،
and that is why we need a killer app of climate policy
ولهذا نحن بحاجة إلى تطبيق خارق لسياسات المناخ
to break through each of these barriers.
لنتجاوز كل هذه الحواجز.
I'm convinced that the road to climate progress in the United States
لقد اقتنعت بأن الطريق للتقدم المناخي في الولايات المتحدة
runs through the Republican Party
تجري من خلال الحزب الجمهوري
and the business community.
ومجتمع الأعمال.
So in launching the Climate Leadership Council,
لذا عند إطلاق مجلس قادة المناخ،
I started by reaching out to a who's who of Republican elder statesmen
بدات بالتواصل مع رجال الدولة الجمهوريين الأكبر سنًا
and business leaders,
و قادة الأعمال،
including James Baker and George Schultz,
من ضمنهم جيمس ببكر و جورج شولتز،
the two most respected Republican elder statesmen in America;
أكثر رجلين تقديرًا ضمن رجال الدولة الجمهوريين في أمريكا،
Martin Feldstein and Greg Mankiw,
مارتن فلدشتاين وجريج مانكيو،
the two most respected conservative economists in the country;
وهما أكثر رجال الأقتصاد المحترمين و المحافظين في البلاد؛
and Henry Paulson and Rob Walton,
وهينري بولسون و روب والتون،
two of the most successful and admired business leaders.
وهما اثنان من أنجح و أمهر قادة الأعمال.
Together, we co-authored
معاً، شاركنا في تأليف
"The Conservative Case For Carbon Dividends."
"الحالة المحافظة لتوزيع حصص الكربون"
This represents the first time
كانت هذه المرة الأولى
that Republican leaders put forth
التي يطرح فيها القادة الجمهوريون
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكرًا.
We presented our plan at the White House
قدمنا فكرتنا في البيت الابيض
two weeks after President Trump moved in.
بعد أسبوعين من وصول الرئيس ترمب له.
Almost every leading editorial board in the country
أيدت كل هيئة تحرير رائدة في البلاد تقريبًأ
has since endorsed our plan,
خطتنا منذ ذلك الحين،
and Fortune 100 companies from a wide range of industries
وشركات Fortune 100 من نطاق واسع من الصناعات
are now getting behind it.
تتبنى ذلك الآن.
So by now you're probably wondering,
لذا لابد أنكم تتساءلون الآن،
what exactly is this plan?
ما هذه الخطة بالضبط؟
Well, our carbon dividends solution is based on four pillars.
حسنًا، حلنا المتعلق بحصص الكربون قائم على أربعة ركائز.
The first is a gradually rising carbon tax.
الأول هو رفع ضريبة الكربون تدريجياً.
Although capitalism is a wonderful system,
على الرغم من أن الرأسمالية هي نظام رائع،
like many operating systems, it's prone to bugs,
مثل جميع أنظمة التشغيل، فأنه عرضة للمشاكل
which, in this case, are called "market failures."
وفي هذه الحاله تدعى "الفشل السوقي."
By far the largest is that market prices fail to take
إلى حد بعيد فإن الأسعار السوقية تفشل في أخذ
social and environmental costs into account.
التكلفة البيئية والمجتمعية بعين الاعتبار.
That means every market transaction is based on incorrect information.
وهذا يعني بأن كل صفقة تجارية تقوم على معلومات خاطئة.
This fundamental bug of capitalism, more than any other single factor,
وهنا تكمن المشكلة الأساسية في الرأسمالية، أكثر من أي عامل آخر،
is to blame for our climate predicament.
وهو إلقاء اللوم على مأزقنا المناخي.
Now in theory, this should be an easy problem to fix.
والآن نظرياً لابد أن تكون هذه مشكلة سهلة الحل.
Economists agree
يوافق خبرلء الاقتصاد
that the best solution is to put a price on the carbon content of fossil fuels,
أن الحل الافضل هو أن نضع سعرًا للمحتوى الكاربوني للوقود الأحفوري،
otherwise known as a carbon tax.
والذي يعرف بضريبة الكربون.
This would discourage carbon emissions
وهذا من شأنه أن يقلل من انبعاثات الكربون
in every single economic transaction,
في كل صفقة اقتصادية فردية،
every day of the year.
في كل يوم من أيام السنة.
However, a carbon tax by itself has proven to be unpopular
ومع ذلك فأن ضريبة الكربون في حد ذاتها أثبتت أنها لا تحظى بشعبية
and a political dead end.
وبأنها الطريق السياسي مسدود أمامها.
The answer is to return all the money raised
والإجابة أم تعود كل الأموال المجموعة
directly to citizens,
مباشرةً للمواطنين
in the form of equal monthly dividends.
في شكل حصص شهرية متساوية.
This would transform an unpopular carbon tax
وهذا من شأته أن ينقل ضريبة الكربون التي لا تحظى بأي شعبية
into a popular and populist solution,
إلى الحل الرائج شعبيًا،
and it would also solve
ومن الممكن أن يحل أيضاً
the underlying psychological barrier that we discussed,
الحواجز النفسية التي ذكرتها سابقًا،
by giving everyone a concrete benefit in the here and now.
من خلال إعطاء الجميع فائدة ملموسة هنا والآن.
And these benefits would be significant.
ولا بد أن تكون هذه الفوائد مؤثرة.
Assuming a carbon tax rate that starts at 40 dollars per ton,
فلنفرض أن ضريبة الكربون تبدأ من 40 دولار للطن الواحد،
a family of four would receive 2,000 dollars per year
فأن الأسرة المكونة من أربعة افراد ستتلقى2000 دولار في السنة
from the get-go.
منذ الانطلاقة الأولى.
According to the US Treasury Department,
ووفقًا لوزارة الخزينة الأمريكية،
the bottom 70 percent of Americans would receive more in dividends
سيتلقى 70 في المئة من الأمريكيين على الأقل حصص كربون أكثر.
than they would pay in increased energy prices.
أكثر مما سيدفعونه مقابل زيادة أسعار الطاقة.
That means 223 million Americans would win economically
وهذا يعني أن 223 مليون أمريكي سوف يكسبون اقتصاديًا
from solving climate change.
من حل مشكلة التغير المناخي.
And that --
وهذا --
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
is revolutionary,
سيكون ثوريًا،
and could fundamentally alter climate politics.
ويستطيع هذا بالأساس تغيير السياسات المناخية.
But there's another revolutionary element here.
ولكن هناك عنصر ثوري آخر هنا،
The amount of the dividend would grow
وهو أن كمية الحصص ستزداد
as the carbon tax rate increases.
مع زيادة ضريبة الكربون.
The more we protect our climate,
كلما حمينا مناخنا أكثر
the more our citizens benefit.
كلما استفاد مواطنونا أكثر.
This creates a positive feedback loop,
هذا يخلق حلقة ردود فعل إيجابية،
which is crucial,
وهو أمر بالغ الأهمية،
because the only way we will reach our long-term emission-reduction goals
لأن الطريق الوحيد لنصل إلى أهدافنا طويلة الأمد في خفض الانبعاثات
is if the carbon tax rate goes up every year.
يكمن في ما إذا كانت ضريبة الكربون تزداد سنويًا.
The third pillar of our program is eliminating regulations
الركيزة الثالثة في برنامجنا هي القضاء على القوانين المناخية
that are no longer needed
التي لن تصبح ضرورية
once a carbon dividends plan is enacted.
بمجرد تشريع خطة حصص الكربون.
This is a key selling point to Republicans and business leaders.
هذه نقطة إقناع أساسية لكل الجمهوريين وقادة الأعمال.
So why should we trade
لذا لماذا لا نبدل
climate regulations for a price on carbon?
القوانين المناخية مقابل سعرٍ للكربون؟
Well, let me show you.
جيد، اسمحوا لي أن أعرض عليكم لماذا.
Our plan would achieve nearly twice the emissions reductions
ستحقق خطتنا حوالي ضعف تقليل الانبعاثات
of all Obama-era climate regulations combined,
من كل القوانين واللوائح في عهد أوباما مجتمعة،
and nearly three times the new baseline
وحوالي ثلاث أضعاف من خط الأساس الجديد
after President Trump repeals all of those regulations.
بعد أن رفض الرئيس ترمب كل هذه القوانين .
That assumes a carbon tax starting at 40 dollars per ton,
بافتراض أن ضريبة الكربون تبدأ من 40 دولار للطن الواحد،
which translates into roughly an extra 36 cents per gallon of gas.
والذي يترجم إلى حوالي 36 سنتا إضافية لكل غالون من الغاز.
Our plan by itself
خطتتنا بنفسها
would meet the high end of America's commitment
سوف تلبي الهدف الأسمى من التزام الولايات المتحدة
under the Paris Climate Agreement,
تحت معاهدة باريس المناخية،
and as you can see,
وكما ترون،
the emissions reductions would continue over time.
سيستمر تقليل الانبعاثات مع مرور الوقت.
This illustrates the power of a conservative climate solution
وهذا يوضح القوة وراء الحل المناخي المحافظ
based on free markets and limited government.
بناءً على السوق الحرة والحكومة المحدودة.
We would end up with less regulation
وهكذا سوف نصل إلى قوانين أقل
and far less pollution at the same time,
وتلوث أقل في نفس الوقت،
while helping working-class Americans get ahead.
بينما نساعد الطبقة العاملة من الأمريكيين للمضي قدماً.
Doesn't that sound like something we could all support?
ألا يبدو ذلك كأمر يمكننا جميعنا دعمه؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
The fourth and final pillar of our program is a new climate domino effect,
ورابع وآخر ركيزة في برنامجنا هو تأثير الدومينو المناخي الجديد،
based on border carbon adjustments.
القائم على التعديلات على حدود الكربون.
Now that may sound complicated,
الآن هذا يبدو معقدًا،
but it, too, is revolutionary,
ولكنه هو أيضًا أمر ثوري،
because it provides us a whole new strategy
لأنه يعطينا استراتيجية جديدة بالكامل
to reach a global price on carbon,
للوصول إبى السعر العالمي للكربون،
which is ultimately what we need.
وهذا ما نحتاجه في نهاية المطاف.
Let me show you an example.
اسمحوا لي أن أعرض عليكم مثالاً.
Suppose Country A adopts a carbon dividends plan,
فلنفرض أن دولة (أ) تبنت خطة حصص الكربون،
and Country B does not.
ودولة (ب) لم تتبنها.
Well, to level the playing field
جيد، من أجل تحسين الأداء على الأرض
and protect the competitiveness of its industries,
و حماية القدرة التنافسية لصناعاتها،
Country A would tax imports from Country B
فإن الدولة (أ) ستفرض ضرائب على وارداتها من الدولة (ب)
based on their carbon content.
بناءً على محتواها من الكربون.
Fair enough.
أمر عادل بما يكفي
But here's where it gets really interesting,
ولكن هنا حيث يصبح الأمر مثيرًا للاهتمام،
because the money raised at the border would increase the dividends
لأن المال المجموع على الحدود سيزيد من الحصص
going to the citizens of Country A.
التي تذهب لمواطني الدولة (أ).
Well, how long do you think it would take the public in Country B to realize
جيد، كم من الوقت تعتقد أنه سوف يستغرق الجمهور في البلد (ب) حتى يدرك
that that money should be going to them,
أن ذلك المال يجب أن يذهب لهم،
and to push for a carbon dividends plan in their own land?
ويدفعون بخطة حصص الكربون في بلدهم؟
Add a few more countries,
أضف القليل من البلدان الأضافية
and we get a new climate domino effect.
وسوف نحصل على تأثير الدومينو المناخي الجديد.
Once one major country or region adopts carbon dividends
حالما تتبنى واحدة من الدول أو المناطق الكبرى حصص الكربون
with border carbon adjustments,
مع تعديل الكربون على الحدود،
other countries are compelled to follow suit.
فالبلدان الأخرى ستكون مضطرة للحذو حذوها.
One by one the dominoes fall.
وواحدة تلو الأخرى تسقط قطع الدومينو.
And this domino effect could start anywhere.
ويمكن لتأثير الدومينو هذا أن يبدأ في أي كان.
My preference, strongly, is the United States,
أنا أفضل جدًا أن يكون في الولايات المتحدة،
but it could also start in the United Kingdom,
ولكن يمكنه أن يبدأ أيضاً في المملكة المتحدة
in Germany or another European country,
في ألمانيا أو أي دولة أوروبية أخرى،
or even in China.
أوحتى في الصين.
Let's take China as an example.
لنأخذ الصين كمثال.
China is committed to reducing greenhouse gas emissions,
الصين ملتزمة بتقليل انبعاثات الغازات الدفيئة
but what its leaders care even more about
ولكن ما يهتم به قادتنا أكثر من ذلك
is transitioning their economy to consumer-led economic development.
هو أن ينقلوا بلادهم إلى تنميةٍ اقتصادية يقودها المستهلك.
Well, nothing could do more to hasten that transition
جيد، مامن شيء يمكنه أن يسرع هذا الانتقال
than giving every Chinese citizen a monthly dividend.
اأثر من إعطاء كل مواطن صيني حصصًا شهرية.
In fact, this is the only policy solution
في الحقيقة، هذا هو الحل القانوني الوحيد
that would enable China to meet its environmental and economic goals
الذي سيمكن الصين من الوصول إلى أهدافها البيئية والاقتصادية
at the same time.
في نفس الوقت.
That's why this is the killer app of climate policy,
هذا هو السبب أن هذا هو التطبيق الخارث لقوانين المناخ،
because it would enable us to overcome
لأنها تمكنها من التغلب
each of the barriers we discussed earlier:
على كل الحواجزالتي سبق أن تطرقنا إليها:
the psychological barrier, the partisan barrier,
الحاجز النفسي، الحاجز الحزبي
and, as we've just seen, the geopolitical barrier.
و كما رأينا الحاجز الجيوسياسي.
And one method of finding what you're looking for
وطريقة وحيدة لإيجاد ما نبحث عنه
is to take out an ad.
هو أن نضع إعلانًا عنه.
So let's read this one together.
لذا دعونا نقرأ هذا سويةً.
Wanted: country to pioneer carbon dividends plan.
مطلوب: بلد يتبنى خطة حصص الكربون
Cost to country: zero.
التكلفة على الدولة: صفر
Starting date: as soon as possible.
تاريخ البدء: أقرب وقت ممكن.
Advantages: most effective climate solution,
الفوائد: أكثر حل مناخي فعال،
popular and populist,
والأكثر شعبيةً،
pro-growth and pro-business,
مؤيدٍ للنمو ومؤيدٍ للتجارة،
shrinks government and helps the working class.
يقلص الحكومة ويساعد الفئة العاملة.
Additional compensation: gratitude of current and future generations,
تعويضات إضافية: امتنان الأجيال الحالية والقادمة،
including my daughter.
من ضمنهم ابنتي.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Chris Anderson: Just one question for you, Ted.
كريس أندرسون: فقط سؤال واحد لك، تيد.
I'm actually not sure
أنا في الحقيقة لست متأكدًا
I've seen a conservative get a standing O at TED before that.
أنني قد رأيت شخصًا محافظًا يقف له الجمهور في TED من قبل.
That's pretty cool.
هذا جميل جدًا.
but some people you talk to in politics
ولكن من الناس من تتحدث لهم من السياسيين
How are you feeling about momentum behind this?
ما هو شعورك حول كمية الزخم وراء ذلك؟
Ted Halstead: So I understand that many are very pessimistic
تيد هالستيد: حسناً، أفهم أن كثيرًا من الناس متشائمون
about what's happening in the United States with President Trump.
حول ما يحدث في الولايات المتحدة مع الرئيس ترمب.
I'm less pessimistic; here's why.
أنا أقل تشائماً؛ وإليك السبب.
The actions of this White House, the early actions on climate,
ما حدث فس البيت الأبيض، الخطوات الأولى بخصوص المناخ،
are just the first move in a complex game of climate chess.
ما هي إلا الحركة الأولى في لعبة معقدةٍ من لعبة شطرنج المناخ.
So far it's been a repeal-only strategy;
لحد الآن كانت استراتيجية إلغاء فقط،
the pressure is going to mount for a replacement program,
وسوف يطبق الضغط للتحول إلى برنامج الاستبدال،
which is where we come in.
والتي ياأتي دورنا من خلالها.
And there are three reasons why, which I'll go through real quickly.
وهناك ثلاثة أسباب لذلك، والتي سأعرضها بسرعة
One, the business community is fundamentally parting ways
الأول، مجتمع الأعمال هو على مفترق طرق
with the White House on climate change.
مع البيت الأبيض في تغيرات المناخ.
In fact, we're finding
وفي الحقيقة ،فقد وجدنا
a number of Fortune 100 companies supporting our program.
أن عددًا من شركات Fortune 100 تدعم برنامجنا.
Within two months, we're going to be announcing
خلال شهرين، سوف نقوم بإعلان
some really surprising names coming out in favor of this program.
بعض الأسماء المميزة والتي أبدت تأييداً لهذا البرنامج.
Two, there is no issue in American politics
الثاني، لا يوجد قضية سياسية أمريكية
where there's a more fundamental gap between the Republican base
توجد بها فجوة أساسية بين القاعدة الجمهورية
and the Republican leadership than climate change.
والقادة الجمهوريين أكثر من تغيرات المناخ.
the big decision up ahead is: Does the administration stay in Paris?
القرار الكبير الذي يلمع في رؤوسنا هو: هل يجب أن تظل الإدارة في باريس؟
Well, let's pan it out both ways.
جيد، دعونا نجليها في كلا الطريقين.
If it stays in Paris, as many are pushing for in the administration,
إذا بقيت في باريس، كما يحبذ الكثيرون،
well then that begs a question: What's the plan?
فهذا يحيلنا إلى سؤال ملح: ما هي الخطة؟
We have the plan.
لدينا الخطة.
But if they don't stay in Paris,
ولكن إذا لم تبق في باريس،
the international pressure will be overwhelming.
فسيكون الضغط الدولي مربكًا.
Our Secretary of State will be asking other countries for NATO contributions,
وسيلتمس وزير خارجيتنا البلدان الأخرى من الناتو للمشاركة،
and they'll be saying, "No, give us our Paris commitment.
وسيقولون، "لا، أعطنا التزام باريس الخاص بنا.
Come through on your commitments, we'll come through on ours."
احترم التزاماتك وسنحترم التزاماتنا."
So, international, business and even the Republican base
لذا فالقاعدة الدولية ، والأعمال، وحتى القاعدة الجمهورية
will all be calling for a Republican replacement plan.
سيدعون جميعًا إلى استبدال المخطط الجمهوري.
TH: Thank you, Chris.
ت. ه : شكراً لك، كريس.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)